Guide to the Hammond Film Script Collection ca. 1935-1996 MSS.076 MSS.076
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series A: French Film Scripts
  - Subseries 7: Various Directors
    - La Femme de l'Aviateur -- Rohmer, Eric, undated; 31142040615471 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Une Femme est Une Femme -- Godard, Jean Luc, undated; 31142040615471 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Femme entre Chien et Loup -- Delraux, Andre, 1977; 31142040615471 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Le Feu Follet -- Malle, Louis, undated; 31142040615471 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - La Fille du Puisatier -- Pagnol, Marcel, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Fort du Fou (1 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Fort du Fou (2 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - La Garde a Vue -- Miller, Claude, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Garou-Garou le Passe-Muraille -- Boyer, Jean, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Gervaise -- Clement, Rene, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Le Gout Des Autres -- Jaqui, Agnes & Bacri, Jean-Pierre, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Le Guerisseur -- Ciampi, Yves, undated; 31142040615489 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Un Homme de Trop -- Costa-Graves, undated; 31142040615497 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - HO -- Enrico, Robert, undated; 31142040615497 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Huis Clos (original) -- Audry, Jacquelline, undated; 31142040615497 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Huis Clos (carbon copy) -- Audry, Jacquelline, undated; 31142040615497 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Innocents in Paris -- Grunwald, Anatole de, undated; 31142040615505 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Les Intrigantes -- Decain, Henri, undated; 31142040615505 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Jeu de Massacre -- Jessua, Alain, undated; 31142040615505 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Les Jeux de l'Amour -- De Broca, Phillipe, undated; 31142040615505 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Les Jeux Son Faites -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615505 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Le Journal d'un Cure de Compagne -- Bresson, Robert, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Jupiter -- Lacombe, Georges, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Justice est Faite -- Cayatte, Andre, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Lettre Morte [TV] -- Dewever, Jean, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Le Lien de Parente -- Rameau, Willy, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - La Ligne Droite (1 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - La Ligne Droite (2 of 2) -- [none], undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Loresque l'Enfant Parait (1 of 2) -- Boisrond, Michel, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Loresque l'Enfant Parait (2 of 2) -- Boisrond, Michel, undated; 31142040615513 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - La Lumiere d'Ete (c.1) -- Gremillon, Jean, 1943; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - La Lumiere d'Ete (c.2) -- Gremillon, Jean, 1943; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Macao (1 of 2) -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Macao (2 of 2) -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Madame de (1 of 2) -- Ophuls, Max, undated; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Madame de (2 of 2) -- Ophuls, Max, undated; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Marie-Chanal contre le Docteur Kah -- Chabrol, Claude, undated; 31142040615521 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Marie la Louve -- Wronecky, Daniel, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Le Matelot 512--[none], undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - La Maternelle -- Diamant-Berger, Henri, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Merlusse -- Pagnol, Marcel, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Les Miserables: Fantine (Premiere Film) -- [none], undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Les Miserables: Cosette et Marius (Deuxieme Film) -- [none], undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Les Miserables: Jean Valjean (Troisieme Film) -- [none], undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Monsieur Vincent (1 of 3) -- Cloche, Maurice, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Monsieur Vincent (2 of 3) -- Cloche, Maurice, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Monsieur Vincent (3 of 3) -- Cloche, Maurice, undated; 31142040615539 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - La Mort d'un Brave -- Villiers, Patty, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - La Mort en ce Jardin (dialogue) -- Bunuel, Luis, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - La Mort en ce Jardin (addenda) -- Bunuel, Luis, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Mortelle Randonnee -- Miller, Claude, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Muertes -- Pottier, Richard, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - La Nuit des Fleurs -- [none], undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - La Nuit est mon Royaum -- Lacombe, Georges, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - La Nuit Fantastique -- L'Herbier, Marcel, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Occupe-toi d'Amelie -- Autant-Lara, Claude, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Olivia -- Audry, Jacqueline, undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Paris vu Par (publicity) -- [none], undated; 31142040615547 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Pas de Vieux Os (1 of 2) -- Mordillat, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Pas de Vieux Os (2 of 2) -- Mordillat, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Le Passe Simple -- Drach, Michael, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Pauline a la Plage -- Rohmer, Eric, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Le Pays d'Ou Je Viens -- Carne, Michael, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Les Petits Engants du Siecle -- Santelli, Claude, 1973; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Les Petites Sirenes -- Andrieux, Roger, undated; 31142040615554 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Pied Nu (Point Mort) -- Roos, Ody, undated; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Pierre et Pau -- Allio, Rene, undated; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Pitchipoi -- Blistene, Marcel, 1960; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Le Point de Fuite -- Gauthier, Bertrand, undated; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Premiere Journee -- [none], undated; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Le Pretre Marie -- [none], undated; 31142040615562 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - La Princesse de Cleves -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - La Putain Respectueuse -- Pagliero, Marcello, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Quai des Orfevres -- Clouzot, Henri-Charles, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Le Quatrieme Sexe -- Gimeno, Alfonso, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - R & J 2000, ou Visa Pour L'Eternite -- Valet, Gerard, 1982; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - La Religieuse -- Rivette, Jacques, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Rendez-Vous a Brave -- Delvaux, Andre, undated; 31142040615570 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Rendez-Vous de Juillet -- Vuattoux, Rene-Gaston, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Retenez Moi…Ou Je Fais Un Malheur -- Gerard, Michel, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Le Rideau Rouge -- Barasq, Andre, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Le Roi de la Chine (version1) -- Cazaneuve, Fabrice, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Le Roi de la Chine (version2) -- Cazaneuve, Fabrice, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Le Roi de Coeur -- De Broca, Philippe, undated; 31142040615588 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Roma Bene -- [none], 1970; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Le Saint Conduit le Bal-- Nahum, Jacques, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Samedi Samedi -- Okan, Bay, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Sang et Lumieres -- Rouquier, Georges, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Le Silencieux (1 of 2) -- Pinoteau, Claude, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Le Silencieux (2 of 2) -- Pinoteau, Claude, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Un Singe en Hiver (c.1) -- Clouzot, Henri-Georges, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Un Singe en Hiver (c.2) -- Clouzot, Henri-Georges, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Un Signe en Hiver -- Verneuil, Henri, undated; 31142040615596 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Un Soir, Un Train -- Delvaux, Andre, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Le Soleil des Voyous -- none], undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Le Souffle au Coeur -- Malle, Louis, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Les Stances a Sophie -- Mizraki, Moshe, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Sylvie et le Fantome -- Autant-Lara, Claude, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Symphonie Pastorale -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Symphonie Pastorale (dialogues) -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615604 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Tamango -- Berry, John, undated; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Tea Party -- Carrere, Jean-Paul, undated; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Tendrement Cruellement Votre -- Wichard, Michel, undated; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - La Tenebreuse Affaire -- Roncoroni, Jean-Louis, 1973; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - La Testamente d'on Poete -- Wichard, Michel, 1970; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Touchez Pas aux Blondes (1 of 2) -- Cloche, Maurice, 1925-1996; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Touchez Pas aux Blondes (2 of 2) -- Cloche, Maurice, 1925-1996; 31142040615612 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Le Transfuge -- Lefebvre, Philippe, 1984; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - 13 Rue de l'Espoir -- Carbonnaux, Norbert, undated; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Trois de Perdues -- [none], undated; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Les Trois Font la Paire -- Guitry, Sacha, undated; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - La Vache et le Prisonnier -- Verneuil, Henri, undated; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - La Vallee Fantome -- Tanner, Alain, undated; 31142040615620 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - La Vengence du Serpent a Plumes -- Oury, Gerard undated, 31142040615638 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - La Veuve et L'Innocent -- Gerin, Pierre, undated; 31142040615638 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Le Vice et La Vertu -- Vadim, Roger, undated; 31142040615638 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Victor -- Heymann, Claude, undated; 31142040615638 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Une Vie -- [none], undated; 31142040615638 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - La Vie a l'Envers -- Jessua, Alain, undated; 31142040615646 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - La Vie Conjugale: Francoise -- Cayette, Andre, undated; 31142040615646 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - La Vie Conjugale: Jean-Marc -- Cayette, Andre, undated; 31142040615646 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Les Vierges de Rome -- Cottafavi, Vittorio, undated; 31142040615646 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - The Viking -- [none], undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 1)
    - Les Visiteurs de Soir -- Carne, Marcel, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 2)
    - Vive la Sociale! -- Mordillat, Gerard, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 3)
    - Le Voleur -- Malle, Louis, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 4)
    - Le Voyageur sans Bagage (Dialogue only) -- Anouilh, Jean, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 5)
    - Z (1 of 2) -- Gavras, Costa, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 6)
    - Z (2 of 2) -- Gavras, Costa, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 7)
    - Zero de Conduite -- Vigo, Jean, undated; 31142040615653 (Box 43A, Folder 8)
    - L'Eternel Retour -- Delannoy, Jean, undated; 31142040615752 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Juliette, ou La Clef des Songes -- Carne, Marcel, undated; 31142040615752 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Monsieur Bien Sous Tous Rapport - Hunebelle, Andre, undated; 31142040615752 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Solo (1 of 2) -- Mocky, Jean Pierre, undated; 31142040615752 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Solo (2 of 2) -- Mocky, Jean Pierre, undated; 31142040615752 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - La Neige it le Feu (1 of 2) -- Pinoteau, Claude, 1990; 31142040615950 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - La Neige it le Feu (2 of 2) -- Pinoteau, Claude, 1990; 31142040615950 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Olivier Olivier -- Holland, Agnieszka, undated; 31142040615950 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Le Pretre (3rd version) -- Holland, Agnieszka, 1986; 31142040615950 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Cache-Cash -- Pinoteau, Claude, 1993; 31142040615968 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 8: Yves Robert
    Film scripts directed by Yves Robert.
    - Arsene Lupin et La Toison D'Or, undated; 31142040615661 (Box 43B, Folder 1)
    - Bebert et L'Omnibus, undated; 31142040615661 (Box 43B, Folder 2)
    - Le Bal des Casse-pieds, undated; 31142040615661 (Box 43B, Folder 3)
    - Clerambard, undated; 31142040615661 (Box 43B, Folder 4)
    - Les Copains, 1964; 31142040615679 (Box 43C, Folder 1)
    - Courage Fuyons, undated; 31142040615679 (Box 43C, Folder 2)
    - Un Elephant ca Trompe Enormement, undated; 31142040615679 (Box 43C, Folder 3)
    - La guerre des boutons, undated; 31142040615679 (Box 43C, Folder 4)
    - Montparnasse Pondichery, 1994; 31142040615687 (Box 43D, Folder 1)
    - Nous Irons Tous Au Paradis, undated; 31142040615687 (Box 43D, Folder 2)
    - Salut L'Artiste, undated; 31142040615687 (Box 43D, Folder 3)
- Series B: Spanish Film Scripts
  - Subseries 1: Luis Bunuel
    Film scripts directed by Luis Bunuel. These scripts are legal-sized.
    - Cumbres Borras Cosas, 1953; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - La Ilision Viaja en Tranvia (c.1), 1953; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - La Ilision Viaja en Tranvia (c.2), 1953; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Nazarin, 1958; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Los Olvidados (c.1), 1950; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Los Olvidados (c.2), 1950; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Robinson Crusoe (English), 1952; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Robinson Crusoe (Spanish), 1952; 31142040615695 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Various Directors
    Film scripts with various directors. Director's name (if provided) is listed after name of film. These scripts are legal-sized.
    - Adios Cordera -- Herrero, Pedro Mario, undated; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Amor Indio & La Virgen de Tizoc - Rodriquez, Ismael, 1956; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - La Canasta -- Traven, B., undated; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - La Casa Chica -- Gavaldon, Roberto, undated; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - La Caza del Conejo -- Saura, Carlos, undated; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Chilam Balam -- De Martino, Inigo, 1955; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Con el Viento Solano -- Comus, Mario, undated; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Corazon, Salvaje -- [none], 1955; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Cuentan de una Mujer -- Ortega, Juan J., 1957; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Dias de Otono -- Traven, B., 1962; 31142040615703 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - En la Palma de su Mano -- Gavaldon, Roberto, 1950; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - El Farsante -- [none], 1956; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - El Gallo de Oro -- Gavaldon, Roberto, 1964; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - La Hiji del Pena -- Sarmiento, Ail Moya, undated; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Hotel Tropical -- Ortega, Juan J., 1954; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Macario -- Traven, B., undated; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Marcellino Pan e Vino -- [none], 1954; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Maria -- Davison, Tito, 1971; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Maria Candelaria -- [none], 1943; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Miercoles de Ceniza -- Gavaldon, Roberto, 1958; 31142040615711 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - No Me Olvides Nunca -- Ortega, Juan J., 1955; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Otra Primavera -- Crevenna, Alfredo B., 1949; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Pepita Jimenez -- [none], undated; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Pedro Paramo -- Velo, Carlos, 1965; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Un Perro Llamado Senor Bossi -- Vajda, Ladislao, undated; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - La Rosa Blanca -- Galvadon, Roberto, 1960; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Los Salvajes -- Baledon, Rafael, 1957; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Si Usted No Puedo--Yo Si -- Soler, Julian, 1950; 31142040615729 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Sixty Dollars -- Alcoriza, Luis, 1967; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Una Solucion Inesperada -- Traven, B., undated; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - La Tia Tula -- [none], 1966; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Tiburoneros -- Alcoriza, Luis, 1962; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - La Tigressa -- Traven, B., undated; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Tlayucan -- Alcoriza, Luis, undated; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Vainilla Bronce y Morir -- Gonzalez, Rogelio, 1956; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Una Ventana a la Vida -- Blake, Alfonso Corona, 1956; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - El Viento Distante - Tarde de Agosto -- Vejar, Sergio, 1964; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - La Visita Que No Toco El Timbre -- Soler, Julian, 1953; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Yo Pecador -- Blake, Alfonso Corona, 1958; 31142040615737 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Desordre -- Assayas, Olivier, undated; 31142040615836 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Macario -- Gavaldon, Roberto, undated; 31142040615836 (Box 58, Folder 2)
- Series C: Italian Film Scripts
  Film scripts in Italian - no director indicated.
  - Il Fornaretto di Venezia, undated; 31142040615745 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Operazione San Gennaro (1 of 2), undated; 31142040615745 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Operazione San Gennaro (2 of 2), undated; 31142040615745 (Box 49, Folder 3)
- Series D: English Language Film Scripts
  - Subseries 1: E. L. Doctorow
    Film scripts based on the writings of E. L. Doctorow
    - Ragtime (1 of 3), April 15, 1976, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Ragtime (2 of 3), April 15, 1976, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Ragtime (3 of 3), April 15, 1976, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Ragtime [Bo Goldman] (1 of 2), July 15, 1979, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Ragtime [Bo Goldman] (2 of 2), July 15, 1979, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller] (1 of 3), Sept. 1979, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller] (2 of 3), Sept, 1979, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller] (3 of 3), Sept, 1979, 31142040615760 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller], Oct. 1979, 31142040615778 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller], April 21, 1980, 31142040615778 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Ragtime [Michael Weller], May 20, 1980, 31142040615778 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: Larry McMurtry
    Film scripts written by Larry McMurtry
    - Cantrell, undated; 31142040615786 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Montana, undated; 31142040615786 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Prince of the City
    Various drafts of the film "Prince of the City," with the respective screenwriter indicated.
    - Prince of the City [1st draft] -- Rabe, David, undated; 31142040615794 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Prince of the City [2nd draft] -- Rabe, David, undated; 31142040615794 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Prince of the City [3rd draft] -- Allen, Jay Presson, undated; 31142040615794 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Prince of the City [4th draft] -- Allen, Jay Presson, undated; 31142040615794 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Various Writers & Directors
    Film scripts with various directors or screenwriters. Director's name (if provided) is listed after name of film.
    - The Amen Corner -- Baldwin, James (writer), undated; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Being There -- Kosinksi, Jerzy (writer), 1979; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - The Big Sleep -- Faulkner, William (writer), 1946; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - The Birds -- Hunter, Evan (writer), 1962; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Brute Force -- Dassin, Jules, 1947; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - The De Gaulle Story -- Faulkner, William (writer), undated; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Endless Love -- Spencer, Scott, 1980; 31142040615802 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Enemies, A Love Story -- Singer, Isaac Bashevis (writer), 1975; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Little Ballerina -- Berger, Ludwig, 1949; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - The Longest Day (1 of 2) -- Ryan, Cornellius (writer), 1961; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - The Longest Day (2 of 2) -- Ryan, Cornellius (writer), 1961; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Midnight Cowboy -- Salt, Waldo (writer), 1968; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - The Paradine Case -- Hecht, Ben (writer), 1943; 31142040615810 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - {no file}, 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Spellbound -- Hecht, Ben (writer), undated; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Strangers on a Train -- Highsmith, Patricia (writer), 1950; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Torn Curtain -- Moore, Brian (writer), (writer)1965; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - True Confessions -- Dunne, John Gregory (writer), 1979; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Walking Down Broadway (1 of 3) - Von Stroheim, Erich, undated; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Walking Down Broadway (2 of 3) - Von Stroheim, Erich, undated; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Walking Down Broadway (3 of 3) - Von Stroheim, Erich, undated; 31142040615828 (Box 57, Folder 8)
- Series E: Gift of Marc Maurette
  These scripts represent the gift from French filmmaker Marc Maurette. This series includes both French and English language scripts, from various directors. Some scripts (when noted) are duplicated elsewhere in the collection.
  - Le Caporal Epingle -- Renoir, Jean (also in Box 19), 1961; 31142040615844 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - The Golden Coach -- Renoir, Jean, undated; 31142040615844 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - La Marseillaise -- Renoir, Jean, undated; 31142040615844 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - La Vie est a nous -- Renoir, Jean, undated; 31142040615844 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - L'Insoutenable Legerete de l'etre - Kaufman, Philip (writer), undated; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - The Unbearable Lightness of Being - Kaufman, Philip (writer), 1986; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Tolerance -- Duneton, Claude, undated; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Carmen -- Rosi, Francesco (adaptation), undated; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Charade -- Donan, Stanley, 1962; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Castle Keep -- Rayfield, David, 1968; 31142040615851 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - La Peau (1 of 3) -- Cavani, Liliana & Katz, Robert, undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - La Peau (2 of 3) -- Cavani, Liliana & Katz, Robert, undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - La Peau (3 of 3) -- Cavani, Liliana & Katz, Robert, undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Le Diable Probablement -- Bresson, Robert, undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Le Diable Probablement (original) -- Bresson, Robert undated, 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - The Sailor from Gibraltar - Isherwood, Christopher (writer), 1964; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Identification d'une feeme (1 of 2) -- Antonioni, M., undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Identification d'une feeme (2 of 2) -- Antonioni, M., undated; 31142040615869 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Ali Baba et les Quarante Voleurs (1 of 2) - Becker, Jacques (also Box 15), undated; 31142040615877 (Box 62, Folder 1)